Oh. My. Gods.
Shazam! Fury of the Gods is a comedy, action, fantasy
film directed by David F. Sandberg.
Billy Batson and his foster siblings, who transform into superheroes by saying "Shazam!", are forced to get back into
action and fight the Daughters of Atlas, who they must stop from using a weapon that could destroy the world.
Shazam, played by Zachary Levi.
Billy Batson, played by Asher Angel.
Freddy Freeman, played by Jack Dylan Grazer.
Anthea, played by Rachel Zegler.
Super Hero Freddy, played by Adam Brody.
Super Hero Eugene, played by Ross Butler.
Fury of the Gods is a 2023 American superhero film
based on the DC character Shazam.
Produced by New Line Cinema, DC Films, and the Safran
Company, and distributed by Warner Bros.
Pictures, it is the sequel to Shazam!
(2019) and the 12th installment in the DC Extended Universe (DCEU).
Directed by David F.
Sandberg and written by Henry Gayden and Chris Morgan, it stars Zachary Levi, Asher
Angel, Jack Dylan Grazer, Rachel Zegler, Adam Brody, Ross Butler, D.
Cotrona, Grace Caroline Currey, Meagan Good, Lucy
Liu, Djimon Hounsou, and Helen Mirren.
The plot follows Billy Batson / Shazam and his foster siblings as
they fight the Daughters of Atlas to save the Earth.
A sequel to Shazam!
began development shortly after its release in April 2019, with Gayden returning as
writer, and Morgan joining soon after to revise Gayden's screenplay.
Sandberg and Levi were also set to return by that December.
The title and the rest of the returning cast were confirmed in August 2020, with
Zegler, Mirren and Liu cast as the daughters of Atlas in early 2021.
Filming began that May in Atlanta, Georgia, and concluded in August.
Fury of the Gods premiered at the Fox Village Theatre in Los Angeles on March
14, 2023, and was released in the United States on March 17.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who
considered it inferior to its predecessor.
It was a box-office failure, grossing $134.1 million worldwide
against a production budget of $110–125 million.
The film explores themes of superhero, end of the world, super
power, aftercreditsstinger, duringcreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted.